So in this video, we are going to see how to read and write data blocks using this MFC and STM eight
microcontroller.
So first thing you have to do is you have to select the correct port, which you can easily see in this
select box.
So let's just open and you have to click on State Select Normal over here, right?
So you have to click on normal, so all the other options will be activated after it.
So all you have to do is first, let's just check out the Uid.
So we can do read ID.
ID read.
And you might have to click at two times.
Right.
So over here you can see it's saying serial number.
So serial number is same as Uid.
So this is the Uuid of the card.
And we can.
Confirm it by looking at the data block zero.
So over here you can see the password or key A is same.
So key A is f, f, f, f, f f, which is the default configuration in transport mode because each
method card which we get from any seller, it always comes with the transport configuration.
And in transport configuration, this is the default key.
So let's just do read data.
So you can see the first four bytes are exactly similar to the four bytes of Uid.
So the first four bytes of Uid are from block zero.
Of Sector Zero.
So this is the one thing.
And the other data which you are, which you can see over here is the manufacturer's data.
So we usually don't use that data for the card manufacturers, so we don't use this block.
We just get the Uid from the block and we utilize this Uid if we need it in some purpose.
So this is what the Uid is.
Now let's just read some other block.
Let's just read data block one.
And you can see data block one contains all the zeros because in transport configuration, all the data
blocks are in zero.
So there is no data or there is only zero.
So we can write our own data as well.
So we will see how to write data in a moment using this tool.
So over here there are few other commands as well.
Request and call, which is anti-collision and then select.
These three commands are exactly equal to read.
So we can press ID rate.
It will do the same task.
It will perform all these three task using this command, but we can do it separately as well.
So we can do request and then anti-collision and then select.
So this is what this card is doing.
So this is how we get the ID Uuid and this is how we read the block.
We can read any block.
Let's just say block five.
You might have to click it two times.
So it's not able to read Block five.
And the reason is we have changed the Uuid.
Sorry, we have changed the key A and key B of block five because Block five is in Sector one and we
have modified sector one in our previous section.
When we were playing with this card in 1 to 2 U.S..
Right.
So we have updated this section.
You can also keep the data sheet open or the memory structure open, so it will help you a lot while
doing the programming.
So this is the memory structure of one mifare classic cards.
So over here you can see block five is in sector one.
And we I already told you that we have modified its sector trailer in 1 to 2.
So.
Let me put the correct key, which we have modified in 1 to 2 U.S..
So the correct key is.
A.
So now let's just try to read a block five, which is in.
Uh, sector one, as I told you.
So let's just try to read this block.
The dusky.
So you can see the read data blocks is success and we can only see data in hexadecimal over here in
in 1 to 2 you as there was an option to see the data in SRC format as well.
But this is not a big issue.
You can just copy this.
And you can open any hex converter and you can paste it over here.
And you can see the message.
So this is my message one.
You can see it exactly what it was written in.
So this is how you convert a hexa to SQ.
And this is how you read data.
Now let's just go into some new block.
So let me modify the keys over here.
By the way, this software only accepts capital letters, so make sure you use capital letters.
And let's just try to use.
Block 16in sector four.
So let's just start with block 16 in sector four.
So.
We have to write 16 over here and we can read data.
By the way, in the in 1 to 2 view the data address blocks were in hexadecimal.
So you have to give address in hexadecimal.
Right.
But in this software, the you can directly give address block in decimal.
You don't need to put hexadecimal over here.
Right?
So you just you can just use 16 as a data block and you just have to do read data.
Data read.
And you can see the data block is empty.
So let's just write this data.
The same data over here as well.
So all you have to do is data write.
So it will write this data, right?
And we can do data read again and you can see the change data.
So whatever data you want to write, let's just suppose you want to write.
This is my message.
Uh.
One, two, three.
Over here.
I have to.
Let's just open another.
Uh sk2.
Hexa converter.
So over here there is another converter which we can use.
So.
Let's just try to write this data.
So this is the hexadecimal, which you have to write it over here.
454.
68.
69.
73.
2069.
20.
60.
So it should capital.
So.
79.
2031.
32.
Again, 60.
And 73.
And 67.
So we'll write this data on block 16.
And we will do right data.
So this data is written successfully and we can do read data.
So this is how you read and write data using this tool on MFC 5 to 2 module, which is with STM eight
microcontroller.
Right.
So this is how you write data on this microcontroller.
And in the next video we are going to see how to modify the keys in sector trailer.
So it's also very simple.